# **GESER DUGAROV, Ph.D.**

email: geserdugarov@gmail.com

**mobile**: +7-913-703-1014

languages: English (advanced), Russian (native)

**location**: Novosibirsk, Russia

#### **SUMMARY**

Helping professionals to work smarter, not harder by creating automatic systems for their routine. Made transition to data-driven R&D in the IT industry after 12 yrs in fundamental research. Holds a degree of a Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.) in Geophysics. Experienced in project and research management.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Python, Docker, Git, Linux, Matlab

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## ML Research Engineer,

<u>Digital Research</u> (spinoff of <u>Digital Clouds</u>)

II/2022 – current

• Time-reporting system for vehicles monitoring in the construction industry (project manager role).

Python, Docker, Git, Linux

Senior Researcher, X/2009 – current

Trofimuk Institute of Petroleum Geology and Geophysics SB RAS

- 5 years in a row of personal projects supporting by main foundations (Russian Foundation for Basic Research, 2017-2018, 2019-2021; Russian Science Foundation, 2019-2021).
- Plugin for AVAZ inversion embedded in Petrel, Schlumberger, the most used software for interpretation. Project manager role. Transfer of the technology from fundamental research to business.
- 4 graduate students: 3 MSc (2022\*2, 2020), 1 BSc (2020).
- «The best young researcher in Earth science organizations» award from The Government of Novosibirsk (2019).
- Trofimuk Memorial Medal Award from the employer (for significant contribution in the institute work, 2021).

Python, Matlab, Git, Wolfram Mathematica (symbolic computation).

Research Associate (II/2014 – IV/2019), Research Assistant (X/2009 – II/2014)

Engineer IX/2013 – V/2017

Nuclear Safety Institute RAS, Novosibirsk Branch

(4 years)

- Developed automated testing system with visualization of modelling results (comparing with experimental data).
- Updated closure relationships for two-phase coolant flow leading to more robust numerical modelling.

C++, Python, SVN.

#### **EDUCATION**

PhD, Geophysics, X/2009 – XII/2013

Trofimuk Institute of Petroleum Geology and Geophysics SB RAS

(4 years)

MSc, Computational and Applied Mathematics,

IX/2004 - VI/2009

**Novosibirsk State University** 

(5 years)

#### **CERTIFICATES**

- <u>Deep Learning Specialization</u>, Coursera (2021).
- Machine Learning, Coursera (2021).

#### **PROJECTS**

- XII/2019 VIII/2021 AVAZ inversion of local object anisotropy parameters from 3D seismic data *Role*: **project manager**. *Team size*: 7. Customer: NTC NIS-Naftagas, Serbia.
- VII/2019 VI/2021 Acoustic properties and internal structure of hydrate-bearing coal samples *Role*: head of the project. *Team size*: 5. Supported by RSF, grant No. <u>19-77-00068</u>.

#### **HONORS AND AWARDS**

- Trofimuk Memorial Medal Award from Trofimuk Institute of Petroleum Geology and Geophysics SB RAS (2021).
- "The best young researcher in Earth science organizations" from the Government of Novosibirsk (2019).

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Author and coauthor of more than 50 scientific publications. Full publication track record could be found on <a href="https://geserdugarov.github.io">https://geserdugarov.github.io</a>, also in <a href="https://geserdugarov.github.io">WoS</a> and <a href="https://geserdugarov.github.io">Scopus</a> databases.

#### **HOBBIES**

- Going to the gym on a regular basis (since 2019).
- Reading developmental psychology and business management books.

Updated: 15.07.2022

The last updates could be found on <a href="https://geserdugarov.github.io">https://geserdugarov.github.io</a>